Park Place, The Gallery of Art Research, Inc. and Paula Cooper Gallery
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Park Place, The Gallery of Art Research, Inc. records and Paula Cooper Gallery records
1961-2006
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Park Place, The Gallery of Art Research, Inc. and Paula Cooper Gallery
49.8 linear feet
The records of the New York artist-cooperative Park Place, The Gallery of Art Research, Inc. and the Soho contemporary art gallery Paula Cooper Gallery measure 49.8 linear feet and date from 1961 to 2006. The collection documents the founding of the Park Place Gallery and its artists through correspondence, artists' files, photographic materials, financial records, printed materials, and scattered business records. The bulk of the collection is Paula Cooper Gallery records; nearly two-thirds of which are artists' files containing a variety of materials such as correspondence, printed materials, and photographic materials. Also found is additional business correspondence, business records, financial records, and printed materials for Paula Cooper Gallery, as well as a handful of records from Paula Johnson Gallery.
Provenance
Park Place, The Gallery of Art Research, Inc. records and Paula Cooper Gallery records were donated by Paula Cooper, director of the galleries, in two accessions in 2006 and 2009.
Related Material
Related collections found among the holdings of the Archives of America include a sound recording of a lecture given by Paula Cooper (Museum of Fine Arts, Boston sound recordings, May 18, 1983-February 8, 1984); audio tapes which include Paula Cooper (Bruce D. Kurtz video and audio recordings and papers, 1966-1995); and two silent 16mm films by Kenny Schneider (Park Place Gallery artists films, 1967.)
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Historical Note
The artists' cooperative Park Place, The Gallery of Art Research, Inc. opened in November 1965 at 542 West Broadway, showing the work of ten young contemporary artists. The cooperative did not represent an art movement, but frequently exhibited large-scale, non-figurative, geometric paintings and sculptures.
Many of the gallery's artists had attended art school in California and shared similar ideas about art, community, and collaboration. Since 1962, they had been informally exhibiting together at 79 Park Place and other various New York City locations under the name Park Place Gallery. With the successes of their informal exhibitions, and the loss of their lease at 79 Park Place, the group formalized their cooperative under the umbrella non-profit, Art Research, Inc. in 1965.
The cooperative was comprised of five sculptors, five painters, and five collectors. Members included sculptors Mark di Suvero, Peter Forakis, Robert Grosvenor, Tony Magar, and Forrest Myers; painters Dean Fleming, Tamara Melcher, David Novros, Edwin Ruda, and Leo Valledor; and collectors Virginia Dwan, Allen and Betty Guiberson, J. Patrick Lannan, Vera List, and John and Lupe Murchison. The collectors each donated an artwork by one of the artists for sale in the gallery, as well as financed the gallery's annual operating budget. As compensation, each collector was given one major work of art by each artist every year.
Paula Cooper (nee. Johnson) joined Park Place Gallery in 1966 and she became director in late 1966-early 1967. Previously, from 1964-1966, she ran Paula Johnson Gallery, showing artwork by Bob Thompson and other young artists.
Park Place, The Gallery of Art Research, Inc. had its first group show in February 1966. In addition to showing art, the gallery occasionally held jazz sessions and other art-related gatherings. The gallery physically closed at the end of July 1967. However, Paula Cooper continued managing the sale of artwork and organized exhibitions at various locations. The final exhibition of Park Place Gallery artists was held at M.I.T. in late spring of 1968.
Paula Cooper opened Paula Cooper Gallery in Soho at 96 Prince Street in 1968. Her gallery is often credited as being the first gallery in Soho and thus paved the way for the migration of uptown galleries to the neighborhood. From the beginning, the gallery showed primarily conceptual and minimalist art and she continued representing some of the Park Place artists. Artists represented by Paula Cooper Gallery and found in this collection include Jennifer Bartlett, Dara Birnbaum, Peter Campus, Michael Hurson, Zoe Leonard, Robert Mangold, Elizabeth Murray, Cady Noland, Adrian Piper, Ulrich Rückriem, Edwin Ruda, Alan Shields, the estate of Tony Smith, Joseph White, Chris Wilmarth, Kes Zapkus, and many others. The gallery continues to operate in Chelsea on West 21st Street.
Sources consulted include "Reimaging Space: the Park Place Gallery Group in 1960s New York" by Linda Dalrymple Henderson, published by Blanton Museum of Art, 2008; and, "Art and Space: Park Place and the beginning of the Paula Cooper Gallery," by Liza Kirwin, 2007 (http://www.aaa.si.edu/exhibitions/paula-cooper).
Scope and Content Note
The records of the New York artist-cooperative Park Place, The Gallery of Art Research, Inc. and the Soho contemporary art gallery Paula Cooper Gallery measure 49.8 linear feet and date from 1961 to 2006. The collection documents the founding of the Park Place Gallery and its artists through correspondence, artists' files, photographic materials, financial records, printed materials, and scattered business records. The bulk of the collection is Paula Cooper Gallery records; nearly two-thirds of which are artists' files containing a variety of materials such as correspondence, printed materials, and photographic materials. Also found is additional business correspondence, business records, financial records, and printed materials for Paula Cooper Gallery, as well as a handful of records from Paula Johnson Gallery.
The collection is divided in three series, one series for each gallery represented in this collection. The records in each series are not comprehensive and do not represent the full scope of operations at each gallery. Due to the original arrangement of materials, some records related to Park Place Gallery are found in Series 3, and scattered records related to Paula Cooper Gallery are found in Series 2. Researchers are encouraged to reference both series.
Series 1, Paula Johnson Gallery records, contains six folders and includes an artist file for Bob Thompson; two ledger pages of accounts receivables; scattered exhibition announcements and flyers; two photographs of artwork by Vernon Lobb; tax records, and a handful of legal organizational records.
Park Place, The Gallery of Art Research, Inc. records are filed in Series 2 and is arranged in five subseries: correspondence, business files, artists' files, financial records, and printed materials. The correspondence is between gallery employees and clients, museums, and other galleries regarding artwork inquiries, sales and exhibitions. Business files are limited in scope and include documents related to the founding of the gallery, a guest book, and one folder of legal and financial records. Artists' Files for eight of the ten Park Place Gallery artists are found: Dean Fleming, Peter Forakis, Tony Magar, Tamara Melcher, Forrest Myers, David Novros, Edwin Ruda, and Leo Valledor. Not present in this collection are files for Mark di Suvero and Robert Grosvenor. Artists' Files contain a variety of materials including artists' statements, bibliographies, biographies, correspondence, exhibition flyers, interview transcripts, clippings and other printed materials, and photographic materials. Financial Records include check ledgers, a general ledger, paid bill receipts, sales invoices, tax forms, and other miscellaneous financial and banking records. Printed Materials include newspaper clippings, gallery announcements, an interview transcript, a handwritten gallery floor plan, and a poster for the 1964 Park Place Invitational Show drawn by Mark di Suvero with artists' names handwritten by Robert Grosvenor.
The bulk of the collection is the records of Paula Cooper Gallery, Series 3. This series contains similar materials as Series 2 and is arranged in the same five subseries. Correspondence includes responses to appraisal requests (1968-1997) and copies of outgoing gallery correspondence from 1985-1999. Business Files contain documentation related to advertising and renovations to the gallery, as well as an artwork inventory book from the early years of the gallery's operation. The bulk of this series is comprised of Artists' Files which contain varied materials such as correspondence with artists, museums, and galleries regarding installations, artwork fabrication, and other business; biographies and bibliographies; exhibition files; printed materials; and photographic materials of artwork and installations. There is considerable documentation for artists Jennifer Bartlett, Peter Campus, Zoe Leonard, Elizabeth Murray, Alan Shields and the estate of Tony Smith. Sales invoices, consignment records, payment ledgers, cancelled checks and other financial materials are found in Financial Records. Printed Materials are comprised of some newspaper and magazine clippings, an interview transcript, and a copy of a manuscript.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 3 series:
Series 1: Paula Johnson Gallery, 1963-1967 (Box 1; 6 folders)
Series 2: Park Place, The Gallery of Art Research, Inc., 1961-1973, 1989 (Boxes 1-4, 50-51, OV 52; 4.1 linear feet)
Series 3: Paula Cooper Gallery, 1962-2006 (Boxes 4-49, 51; 45.7 linear feet)
Names and Subject Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms:
Subjects:
Bartlett, Jennifer, 1941-; Campus, Peter, 1937-; Fleming, Dean; Forakis, Peter; Leonard, Zoe; Magar, Anthony, 1936-; Melcher, Tamara; Murray, Elizabeth, 1940-; Myers, Forrest Warden, 1941-; Novros, David, 1941-; Ruda, Edwin, 1922-; Shields, Alan, 1944-; Smith, Tony, 1912-1980; Valledor, Leo
Subjects-Topical:
Art galleries, Commercial
Types of Materials:
Interviews; Photographs; Transcripts
Names:
Cooper, Paula, 1938-; Di Suvero, Mark, 1933-; Grosvenor, Robert, 1937-; Thompson, Bob, 1937-1966;; Park Place Gallery Art Research, Inc.; Paula Cooper Gallery; Paula Johnson Gallery
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Paula Johnson Gallery, 1963-1967, Series 1:; (Box 1; 6 folders)
  This series is comprised of six folders of records from the Paula Johnson Gallery, including an artist file for Bob Thompson; two ledger pages of accounts receivables; scattered exhibition announcements and flyers; two photographs of artwork by Vernon Lobb; tax records, and a handful of legal organizational records.
  Folders are arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  - Accounts, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Artists' File, Bob Thompson, 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Financial and Tax Records, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, circa 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Printed Materials, circa 1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Sirota, Krause and Gleason, 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Park Place, The Gallery of Art Research, Inc., 1961-1973, 1989, Series 2:; (Boxes 1-4, 50-51, OV 52; 4.1 linear feet)
  Additional records related to Park Place Gallery are found in Series 3; researchers are encouraged to reference both series.
  The series is arranged as 5 subseries:
  2.1: Correspondence, 1964-1968
  2.2: Business Files, 1965-circa 1970
  2.3: Artists' Files, 1961, 1964-1973
  2.4: Financial Records, 1965-1972
  2.5: Printed Materials, 1964-1972, 1989
  - Correspondence, 1964-1968, 2.1:
    The Park Place Gallery correspondence is between the former director John Gibson, Paula Cooper, and gallery assistants to clients, museums, and other galleries regarding artwork inquiries, sales, and exhibitions. Also found is one folder of requests for Park Place Gallery buttons. Folders are arranged alphabetically by correspondent's last name; button inquiries are filed at the end of the subseries.
    - Correspondence, A-B, 1965-1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, C-D, 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, Denver [and Misc.], 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, E-G, 1965-1968 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, H-M, 1964-1968 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, N-R, 1965-1968 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, S-T, 1965-1968 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, U-Z, 1965-1968 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Park Place Gallery Buttons, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Business Files, 1965-circa 1970, 2.2:
    Found are documents related to the founding of Park Place, The Gallery of Art Research, Inc., a guest book, and one folder of various legal and financial records. Folders are arranged alphabetically by folder title.
    - Beldock, Levine and Hoffman, 1965-1968, circa 1970 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Guest Book, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Park Place, The Gallery of Art Research, Inc., circa 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Park Place, The Gallery of Art Research, Inc. Organizing Documents, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Artists' Files, 1961, 1964-1973, 2.3:
    Files for eight of the ten Park Place Gallery artists are found here: Dean Fleming, Peter Forakis, Anthony (Tony) Magar, Tamara Melcher, Forest Myers, David Novros, Edwin Ruda, and Leo Valledor. There are no files for Mark di Suvero and Robert Grosvenor; however, a handful of artwork slides are found. Additional material related to Edwin Ruda is located in Series 3. Materials are varied and include artists' statements, bibliographies, biographies, correspondence, exhibition flyers, interview transcripts, clippings and other printed materials, and photographic materials. Folders are arranged alphabetically by artist's last name; photographic materials are generally found at the end of the artists' materials. Folders containing materials regarding multiple Park Place Gallery artists and miscellaneous artists are arranged at the end of the subseries.
    - Fleming, Dean, 1965-1973, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 20-21)
    - Fleming, Dean and Anthony Magar Exhibition (Dec. 19, 1965 - Jan. 20, 1966), circa 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Forakis, Peter, 1966-1968, (Includes original color drawings) (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Forakis, Peter (Box 1)
      - Correspondence, 1961, 1966-1973 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - Teaching Jobs, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Slides, 1966, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Magar, Anthony, Photographs, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Melcher, Tamara, circa 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Melcher, Tamara, Slides, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Melcher, Tamara and David Novros, Slides (Duplicates), circa 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Myers, Forest, 1965-1974 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Myers, Forest (Box 2)
      - Albany Mall Photos, Model, circa 1970-1973 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Anti-War Negatives, circa 1968-1973 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence, 1969-1973 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Photographs (1964-1970), circa 1964-1972, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
      - Slides, 1966-1971 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Slides of Early Pieces, 1966, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Novros, David, circa 1966-1970 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Novros, David, Slides, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Ruda, Edwin, Photographs of Early Work (1964-1967), circa 1964-1968, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 11-12)
    - Valledor, Leo, circa 1965-1971, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 13-14)
    - Valledor, Leo, Slides, circa 1964-1967 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Park Place Gallery Artists (Box 2)
      - Original Park Place Gallery Photo Book and Biographies, circa 1964-1968 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Photographic Materials, circa 1965-1967 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Photographs, circa 1964-1968, (3 folders) (Box 2, Folder 18-20)
      - Slides, circa 1965-1967 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - Transparencies, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Miscellaneous Artists (Box 2)
      - Biographies, circa 1967-1969 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - Slides, 1966-1971 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Financial Records, 1965-1972, 2.4:
    Financial Records include check ledgers, a general ledger, paid bill receipts, sales invoices, tax forms, and other miscellaneous financial and banking records. Folders are arranged alphabetically by folder title.
    - Accounting Information, Misc., 1967-1970 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Cancelled Checks (Jan. - Nov. 1967), 1967, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 2-3)
    - Check Ledgers (Dec. 1965 - Apr. 1968), 1965-1968, (Oversized materials housed in Box 50, Folders 1-3) (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Deposit Receipts (Dec. 1965 - Apr. 1968), 1965-1968 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - General Ledger (Feb. - Sept. 1968), 1968 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Insurance, 1966-1968 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - John Gibson Suit, 1966-1970 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Multiples, Inc. [Bills], 1967 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Paid Bills (Oct. 1965 - Dec. 1968), 1965-1968, (9 folders) (Box 3, Folder 10-18)
    - Paid Bills, John D. Schiff, 1965-1967 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Paid Bills, Treitel-Gratz Co., Inc., 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Petty Cash, 1966-1967, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 21-22)
    - [Sales Invoices (1966) and Quarterly Invoices to Patrons], 1965-1967 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Sales Invoices (1967), 1967 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Statement of Revenue and Expenses (Sept. 16, 1968 - Aug. 31, 1969), 1969 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Tax Bulletins, 1966-1972 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Taxes (1966), 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Taxes (1967), 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Check Ledgers (Dec. 1965 - Apr. 1968), 1965-1968, (3 ledgers; Oversized materials from Box 3, Folder 4) (Box 50, Folder 1-3)
  - Printed Materials, 1964-1972, 1989, 2.5:
    Printed Materials include newspaper clippings, gallery announcements, a handwritten gallery floor plan, a poster for the 1964 Park Place Invitational Show drawn by Mark di Suvero with artists' names handwritten by Robert Grosvenor, and a 1988 interview transcript with Paula Cooper discussing Park Place Gallery. The bulk of printed materials related to specific artists are filed in the Artists' Files subseries. Folders are arranged alphabetically by folder title.
    - Clippings, 1965-1972, (2 folders; Oversized materials housed in Box 51, Folders 1-2) (Box 4, Folder 7-8)
    - DropCity Magazine, "The Being Bag," circa late 1960s (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Interview Transcript with Paula Cooper re: Park Place (1988), 1989 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Park Place Gallery Announcements, 1966-1970 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Park Place Gallery Floor Plan, circa 1966, (Oversized material housed in OV 52) (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Park Place Invitational Show Poster (Mar. - Apr. 1964) [Names handwritten by Robert Grosvenor], 1964, (Oversized material housed in OV 52) (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Oversized Newspaper Clippings, 1965-1972, (2 folders; Oversized materials from Box 4, Folder 7 and arranged at bottom of box due to fragility) (Box 51, Folder 1-2)
    - Park Place Gallery Floor Plan, circa 1966, (Oversized material from Box 4, Folder 13) (Box OV 52)
    - Park Place Invitational Show Poster (Mar. - Apr. 1964) [Names handwritten by Robert Grosvenor], 1964, (Oversized material from Box 4, Folder 14) (Box OV 52)
- Paula Cooper Gallery, 1962-2006, Series 3:; (Boxes 4-49, 51; 45.7 linear feet)
  Additional records related to Paula Cooper Gallery are found in Series 2; researchers are encouraged to reference both series.
  3.1: Correspondence, 1968-1999
  3.2: Business Files, 1968-1996, bulk 1980s-1990s
  3.3: Artists' Files, 1962-2006, bulk mid-1970s-early 2000s
  3.4: Financial Records, 1967-1984, 1992-1996
  3.5: Printed Materials, 1966-1980, 1991
  - Correspondence, 1968-1999, 3.1:
    Correspondence contains responses to appraisal requests (1968-1997) and outgoing gallery correspondence (1985-1999). Nearly all of the outgoing correspondence is photocopied letters from the gallery to clients, museums, and other galleries regarding inquiries into artists and artwork. Folders are arranged alphabetically by type of correspondence, then roughly chronological according to original order.
    - Artwork Valuations (1968-1978), 1968-1978 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Artwork Valuations (1979), 1979 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Artwork Valuations (1980), 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Artwork Valuations (1981), 1980-1982 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Artwork Valuations (1982), 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Artwork Valuations (1983), 1983 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Artwork Valuations (1984), 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Artwork Valuations (1985), 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Artwork Valuations (1986), 1985-1987 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Pending Evaluations, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Artwork Valuations [1987], 1986-1987, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Artwork Valuations (1988), 1987-1989, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 26-27)
    - Artwork Valuations (1989), circa 1984-1989 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Insurance Evalutions, 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Artwork Valuations (1990), 1987-1990 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Artwork Valuations (1991), 1987-1991 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Artwork Valuations (1994), 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Artwork Valuations (1995), 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Artwork Valuations (1996), 1994-1996 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Artwork Valuations (1997), 1997 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Pending Appraisals, 1987-1999, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 9-10)
    - Outgoing Correspondence (Jan. - June 1985), 1985, (6 folders) (Box 5, Folder 11-16)
    - Outgoing Correspondence (July - Dec. 1985), 1985, (6 folders) (Box 6, Folder 1-6)
    - Outgoing Correspondence (Jan. - Dec. 1986), 1985-1986, (12 folders) (Box 6, Folder 7-18)
    - Outgoing Correspondence (Jan. 1987), 1987 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Outgoing Correspondence (Jan., Apr. - Dec. 1988), 1988, (10 folders) (Box 7, Folder 1-10)
    - Outgoing Correspondence (Jan. - Sept. 1989), 1988-1989, (9 folders) (Box 7, Folder 11-19)
    - Outgoing Correspondence (Oct. - Dec. 1989), 1988-1989, (3 folders) (Box 8, Folder 1-3)
    - Outgoing Correspondence (Jan. - Dec. 1990), 1990, (12 folders) (Box 8, Folder 4-15)
    - Outgoing Correspondence (Jan. - Dec. 1991), 1991, (12 folders) (Box 9, Folder 1-12)
    - Outgoing Correspondence (Jan. - Mar. 1992), 1992, (3 folders) (Box 9, Folder 13-15)
    - Outgoing Correspondence (Apr. - Dec. 1992), 1992, (9 folders) (Box 10, Folder 1-9)
    - Outgoing Correspondence (Jan. - Dec. 1993), 1993, (12 folders) (Box 10, Folder 10-21)
    - Outgoing Correspondence (Jan. - Feb. 1994), 1994, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 22-23)
    - Outgoing Correspondence (Mar. - Dec. 1994), 1994, (10 folders) (Box 11, Folder 1-10)
    - Outgoing Correspondence (Jan. - Nov. 1995), 1995, (11 folders) (Box 11, Folder 11-21)
    - Outgoing Correspondence (Dec. 1995), 1995 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Outgoing Correspondence (Jan. - Dec. 1996), 1995-1996, (12 folders) (Box 12, Folder 2-13)
    - Outgoing Correspondence (Jan. - Dec. 1997), 1997, (12 folders) (Box 12, Folder 14-25)
    - Outgoing Correspondence (Jan. - Dec. 1998), 1998-1999, (12 folders) (Box 12, Folder 26-37)
  - Business Files, 1968-1996, bulk 1980s-1990s, 3.2:
    The bulk of the business files are related to advertising and renovations to the gallery. Materials include correspondence, bills, and mockups. Also found is an artwork inventory book, scattered insurance materials, and other general business records. The records found here do not represent the totality of the gallery's daily operations. Folders are arranged alphabetically by folder title.
    - Advertising, 1980-1994, (14 folders) (Box 13, Folder 1-14)
    - Advertising (Box 13)
      - Contracts/Agreements, 1990-1996 (Box 13, Folder 15)
      - Correspondence, 1989-1992, (3 folders) (Box 13, Folder 16-18)